Ronnel Sanchez

UI/UX Designer and Front-End Developer

Email: ronnel.sanchez@gmail.com

Mobile: (63) 927 2197146 Skype: ronnel.sanchez

About Me

Equipped with expertise on Design and Web Development. Designed and developed enterprise level, Responsive and User Centric websites and software. Enjoy learning new technology, design tools, programming language and UI/UX guidelines technic which I believe is the core of every project i do.

Work Experience

UI/UX Designer and Front-End Developer | Dec 2012 - Present

Trend Micro Philippines - Ortigas, Pasig City

- Doing Business Process Analysis roles like, studying business process, presenting new ideas to improve the business flow, producing mock-ups and prototypes, checking the development of the projects and handling the sustain and new request.
- Conducting User Experience research which include observation, interview, A/B testing, mouse flow and heat maps
- Present wireframes, user interaction and process flows ideas to stakeholders using Adobe Photoshop and Axure
- Created low to high fidelity prototypes for web or mobile applications using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, frameworks like Bootstrap, jQuery Mobile UI, and Axure.
- Produced responsive and cross browser design which fits to business and user requirements.
- Created User Centered Design into web/mobile site pages, and native mobile app design.
- Created email newsletters or EDM design and other graphics like logos, icons, motion graphics, video presentations and infographics.

Graphical User Interface Designer | Sept 2012 - Oct 2012

Job and Esther Technologies - Alabang, Muntinlupa City

- Create graphical user interfaces (GUIs) for a variety of software products, including (but not limited to) mobile, web, desktop, games, enterprise applications, communication systems and others.
- Collaborate in the writing and maintenance of a GUI style guide.
- Work with our marketing team to design, edit, and maintain online and offline marketing promotional materials like brochures, banners, posters, logos & print ads.
- Work closely with product managers and software developers to define and design an optimal user experience, user interaction model, workflow and information architecture
- Frame out website designs and provide detail and direction to development staff to implement design using HTML, JavaScript, and CSS
- Create mockup designs when needed using appropriate tools and design programs

UI Designer and Developer | Dec 2010 - Sept 2012

Coding Solution Information Technology - Pagsanjan, Laguna

- Produced websites and PC software design that fits to Business requirements
- Work as front-end developer for Website and Mobile apps
- Work closely with team lead and back-end developer to produce mock-ups, mark-ups and prototypes.

Education

Bachelor of Science in Information Technology | 2008 – 2012

AMA Computer University - Santa Cruz Laguna, Philippines

Website Links

Behancehttps://www.behance.net/ronnelsanchezDribbblehttps://dribbble.com/ronnelsanchezLinkedInhttps://ph.linkedin.com/in/ronnelsanchez

Personal Information

Name Ronnel Sanchez

Birth Day April 12, 1992

Location Philippines

Mobile (+63) 9272197146

Email ronnel.sanchez@gmail.com

Skills

Professional Technical

User Interface Design HTML / HTML 5
User Experience CSS / CSS 3

Front-End Development JavaScript / JQuery

Graphic Design Cross browser development

Front-Motion Design Adobe PhotoShop

Prototyping Adobe After Effects

Wire Framing Adobe Illustrator

Reference

Myn Reyes | User Experience Team Lead
Trend Micro Inc. Philippines
normyn.reyes@gmail.com

Miko Mojica | Marketing Liaison Asian Development Bank miko_jazmine@yahoo.com